http://e-maxx.ru/algo/
algo
Here are 145 algorithms. All the algorithms are given short descriptions and programs in C ++.

Show: last added, last edited algorithms.

You can also download a PDF-book, in which all the articles are collected as one large file.

The algebra (23)
elementary algorithms (20)
Euler function and its calculation [TeX]
Binary exponentiation for O (log N) [TeX]
Euclid's algorithm for finding the GCD (greatest common divisor) [TeX]
The sieve of Eratosthenes [TeX]
Advanced Euclid's algorithm [TeX]
Fibonacci numbers and their rapid calculation [TeX]
The inverse element in the ring modulo [TeX]
Gray code [TeX]
Long arithmetic [TeX]
The discrete logarithm by modulo M by the baby-step-giant-step Shanks algorithm for O (sqrt (M) log M) [TeX]
Diophantine equations with two unknowns: AX + BY = C [TeX]
A modular linear equation of the first order: AX = B [TeX]
The Chinese remainder theorem. The Garner algorithm [TeX]
Finding the degree of the factorial divisor [TeX]
Trinity balanced number system [TeX]
Calculation of the factorial N! modulo P for O (P log N) [TeX]
A search of all the subpatterns of this mask. Estimate 3N for the total number of subpatterns of all masks [TeX]
Primitive root. Algorithm for finding [TeX]
Discrete root extraction [TeX]
The Eratosthenes sieve with the linear time of operation [TeX]
complex algorithms (3)
The BPSW test for the simplicity of numbers for O (log N)
Effective algorithms for factorization: Pollard p-1, Pollard p, Bent, Pollard Monte Carlo, Fermat
Fast Fourier transform for O (N log N). Application to multiplication of two polynomials or long numbers [TeX]
Columns (51)
elementary algorithms (4)
Search in width [TeX]
Search in depth
Topological sorting [TeX]
Searching for connectivity components [TeX]
components of strong connectivity, bridges, etc. (4)
Search for strong connectivity components, graph condensation for O (N + M) [TeX]
Search for bridges for O (N + M) [TeX]
Search for junction points for O (N + M) [TeX]
Search bridges online for O (1) on average [TeX]
shortest paths from one vertex (4)
Dijkstra's algorithm for finding the shortest paths from a given vertex to all other vertices after O (N2 + M) [TeX]
The Dijkstra algorithm for a sparse graph of finding the shortest paths from a given vertex to all other vertices after O (M log N) [TeX]
The Ford-Bellman algorithm finds the shortest paths from a given vertex to all other vertices after O (N M) [TeX]
Levit's algorithm for finding the shortest paths from a given vertex to all other vertices after O (N M)
The shortest paths between all pairs of vertices (2)
Finding the shortest paths between all pairs of vertices of the graph by the Floyd-Worshell method for O (n3) [TeX]
Counting the number of fixed-length paths between all pairs of vertices, finding the shortest paths of a fixed length in O (n3 log k) [TeX]
minimum skeleton (5)
Minimum spanning tree. The algorithm of Prima for O (n2) and for O (m log n) [TeX]
Minimum spanning tree. The Kruskal algorithm for O (M log N + N2)
Minimum spanning tree. The Kruskal algorithm with the data structure 'system of disjoint sets' for O (M log N)
Kirchhoff's matrix theorem. The determination of the number of spanning trees for O (N3)
The code for Prufer. Formula Cayley. Number of ways to make a graph connected [TeX]
cycles (3)
Finding a negative cycle in the graph for O (N M) [TeX]
Finding the Eulerian path or the Eulerian cycle for O (M)
Checking the graph for acyclicity and finding the cycle for O (M)
the smallest common ancestor (LCA) (5)
The smallest common ancestor. A search for O (sqrt (N)) and O (log N) with preprocessing O (N)
The smallest common ancestor. A search for O (log N) with O (N log N) preprocessing (binary lift method)
The smallest common ancestor. A search for O (1) with O (N) preprocessing (the Farah-Colton-Bender algorithm)
The task of RMQ (Range Minimum Query - minimum on a segment). Solution for O (1) with preprocessing O (N)
The smallest common ancestor. The search for O (1) in the offline mode (the Tarjan algorithm) [TeX]
flows and related tasks (10)
The Edmonds-Carp algorithm of finding the maximum flow beyond O (N M2)
The method of pushing the preference of finding the maximum flow beyond O (N4)
Modification of the method of pushing the precedent beyond O (N3)
Flow with constraints
The flow of the minimum cost (min-cost-flow). Algorithm of increasing paths for O (N3 M)
The task of appointments. Solution with the help of min-cost-flow for O (N5)
The task of appointments. The Hungarian algorithm (the Kuhn algorithm) for O (N3) [TeX]
Finding the minimal cut by the Stor-Wagner algorithm for O (N3) [TeX]
Flow of minimum cost, circulation of the minimum cost. Algorithm for deleting loops of negative weight [TeX]
Algorithm Dinitsa finding the maximum flow [TeX]
matching and related tasks (6)
Kuhn's algorithm for finding the largest matching for O (N M) [TeX]
Checking the graph for bi-annuality and dividing into two parts for O (M)
Finding the largest weighted vertex-weighted matching for O (N3)
Edmonds' algorithm for finding the greatest matching in arbitrary graphs for O (N3) [TeX]
Covering the paths of an oriented acyclic graph
Matrix of Tatta. Randomized algorithm for finding the maximum matching in an arbitrary graph [TeX]
the connection (3)
Edge connectivity. Properties and location [TeX]
Vertex connection. Properties and location [TeX]
The construction of a graph with the specified values ​​of the vertex and edge connections and the smallest degree of the vertices [TeX]
K-th paths (0)
inverse problems (2)
The inverse problem SSSP (inverse-SSSP - the inverse problem of shortest paths from one vertex) for O (M)
The inverse problem MST (inverse-MST - the inverse problem of the minimal skeleton) for O (N M2)
Miscellaneous (3)
Coloring the edges of a tree (data structure) is a solution for O (log N)
The task 2-SAT (2-CNF). The solution for O (N + M)
Heavy-light decomposition [TeX]
Geometry (23)
elementary algorithms (10)
The length of the union of segments on the line by O (N log N)
The sign area of ​​the triangle and the predicate 'Clockwise' [TeX]
Checking two segments at the intersection [TeX]
Finding the equation of the line for the interval [TeX]
Finding the intersection point of two straight lines [TeX]
Finding the intersection point of two segments [TeX]
Finding the area of ​​a simple polygon for O (N)
Peak's theorem. Finding the area of ​​the lattice polygon after O (1) [TeX]
The problem of covering segments by points
The centers of gravity of polygons and polyhedra [TeX]
more complex algorithms (13)
The intersection of a circle and a line
Intersection of two circles
The construction of a convex hull by the Graham-Andrew algorithm for O (N log N)
Finding the area of ​​union of triangles. Vertical decomposition method
Checking the point for belonging to a convex polygon beyond O (log N)
Finding an inscribed circle in a convex polygon using a ternary search for O (N log2 C)
Finding an inscribed circle in a convex polygon by contracting the sides for O (N log N) [TeX]
The Voronoi diagram in the two-dimensional case, its properties, application. The simplest algorithm for constructing O (N4) [TeX]
Finding all faces, the outer face of the planar graph for O (N log N) [TeX]
Finding the pair of nearest points by the divide-and-rule algorithm for O (N log N) [TeX]
Convert geometric inversion [TeX]
Search for common tangents to two circles [TeX]
The search for a pair of intersecting segments by the algorithm of a sweeping line for O (N log N) [TeX]
Lines (12)
Z-function of the string and its calculation for O (N) [TeX]
Prefix function, its calculation and application. The Knuth-Morris-Pratt algorithm [TeX]
Algorithms for hashing in tasks on strings
The Rabin-Karp algorithm for finding a substring in a row after O (N)
Analysis of expressions for O (N). Reverse Polish notation [TeX]
The suffix array. The construction of O (N log N) and the use of [TeX]
Suffix automaton. Building beyond O (N) and applying [TeX]
Finding all subpalindromes for O (N) [TeX]
The Lyndon decomposition. The Duval algorithm. Finding the smallest cyclic shift for O (N) time and O (1) memory [TeX]
Algorithm Aho-Corasik [TeX]
Suffix tree. The Ukkonen algorithm [TeX]
Search for all tandem repeats in the line with the Maine-Lorentz algorithm (share-and-conquer) for O (N log N) [TeX]
Data Structures (7)
Sqrt-decomposition [TeX]
Fenwick Tree
The system of disjoint sets [TeX]
Tree of segments [TeX]
Cartesian tree (treap, deramid)
Modifying the stack and queue to find the minimum for O (1)
Randomized heap [TeX]
Algorithms on sequences (3)
The task of RMQ (Range Minimum Query - minimum on a segment)
Finding the longest growing subsequence of O (N2) and O (N log N) [TeX]
The K-th ordinal statistics for O (N)
Dynamics (2)
Dynamics by profile. The task of "parquet"
Finding the largest zero submatrix for O (N M) [TeX]
The linear algebra (3)
The Gauss method of solving a system of linear equations for O (N3) [TeX]
The determination of the rank of the matrix over O (N3)
Calculation of the determinant of the matrix by the Gaussian method for O (N3)
Numerical methods (3)
Integration by the Simpson formula [TeX]
Search for roots by the Newton method (tangents) [TeX]
Ternary search [TeX]
Combinatorics (9)
The binomial coefficients [TeX]
The numbers of Catalan [TeX]
Necklaces [TeX]
Arranging elephants on a chessboard
Correct parenthesis sequences. Finding the lexicographically next, K-th, definition of the number [TeX]
The number of labeled graphs, connected labeled graphs, labeled graphs with K connectivity components [TeX]
Generating combinations of N elements
The Burnside lemma. The theorem of Poya [TeX]
The inclusion-exclusion principle [TeX]
Theory of games (2)
Games on arbitrary graphs. The method of retrospective analysis for O (M)
The theory of Sprague-Grandi. Nim [TeX]
Timetables (3)
The Johnson problem with a single machine [TeX]
The Johnson problem with two [TeX]
Optimal job selection for known completion times and execution times [TeX]
Miscellaneous (4)
The task of Joseph [TeX]
Playing the Fifteen: the existence of a solution [TeX]
The Stern-Broco tree. The Farey Series [TeX]
Search for a sub-array with a maximum / minimum amount for O (N) [TeX]
